Finding aid to the Classes of 1941-1950 records CA.MS.01016
Smith College Archives
Classes of 1941-1950 records
1937-2018
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Class of 1941.
CA.MS.01016
56.437 linear feet (96 containers)
Smith College class officers and individual class members have been archiving their historical materials since 1879. Students from certain years in this class group, 1941 to 1950, experienced collateral effects of World War II as they went about their days on campus. These records consist of notes, examinations, papers, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, and songbooks created and collected by individual class members as well as records of their class as a whole made by class officers. Additionally these records include an array of reunion materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Biographical / Historical
Smith College classes have been archiving their historical material by year since 1879. In addition to the more typical college experience, students from certain years of this particular class group, 1941 to 1950, contended with collateral effects of World War II as they went about their days on campus.
Scope and Contents
The Classes of 1941-1950 records consist of 56.437 linear feet of materials including notes, examinations, papers, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, and songbooks created and collected by individual class members as well as records of their class as a whole made by class officers. Additionally these records include an array of reunion materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
A portion of these materials were transferred to College Archives in 2007, 2008, 2010-2012, 2015-2017. Whenever donation information for a particular set of material is known, it is included in the finding aid below. However, a majority of the material was not formally accessioned and its origins are not currently known.
Arrangement
This collection brings together ten record groups that are arranged chronologically, one per graduating class. However, since some materials are placed in a class record group based on when they were created, and not by whom, materials relelvant to a class may exist in more than one series.
Ashmun, Candace McKee; Smith College. Class of 1943.; Smith College. Class of 1942.; Smith College. Class of 1944.; Smith College. Class of 1945.; Smith College. Class of 1946.; Smith College. Class of 1947.; Smith College. Class of 1949.; Smith College. Class of 1948.; Smith College. Class of 1950.; Ashmun, Candace McKee
- Class of 1941 records, 7 boxes (5.2 linear feet); 5.0 linear feet (7 containers)
  Biographical / Historical
  The Class of 1941 was the sixty-third graduating class of Smith College.
  Scope and Contents
  Please use the following format when citing materials from this record group: Class of 1941 records, Box #, Smith College Archives, Northampton, Massachusetts.
  - Commencement, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Dramatics, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1937-1938 (Box 2125, Folder 5)
  - General, 1939 (Box 2125, Folder 6)
  - Groups, 1937-1941 (Box 2125, Folder 7)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 8)
  - Ivy Day, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 9)
  - Ivy Day-Photographs, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 10)
  - Junior Prom, 1940 (Box 2125, Folder 11)
  - Junior Prom-Garden Party, 1940 (Box 2125, Folder 12)
  - Junior Ushers, 1940 (Box 2125, Folder 13)
  - Last Sing, 1941 (Box 2125, Folder 14)
  - Class Letters, 1967-2003 (Box 2125, Folder 15)
  - Officers (Box 2126, Folder 1)
  - Rally Day, 1941 (Box 2126, Folder 2)
  - Reunions, 1942 (Box 2126, Folder 3)
  - Reunions, 1951 (Box 2126, Folder 4)
  - Reunions, 1956 (Box 2126, Folder 5)
  - Reunions, 1961 (Box 2126, Folder 6)
  - Reunions, 1966 (Box 2126, Folder 7)
  - Reunions, 1971 (Box 2126, Folder 8)
  - Reunions, 1976-1986 (Box 2126, Folder 9)
  - Reunions, 1991 (Box 2126, Folder 10)
  - Reunions-Scrapbook, 1991 (Box 2126, Folder 11)
  - Reunions, 2001 (Box 2126, Folder 12)
  - Songs, undated (Box 2126, Folder 13)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1939 (Box 2126, Folder 14)
  - Sophomore Push Committee, 1939 (Box 2126, Folder 15)
  - Class Supper, 1941 (Box 2126, Folder 16)
  - Year Book, 1941 (Box 2126, Folder 17)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: A-F, 1991 (Box 2127, Folder 1)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: F-N, 1991 (Box 2127, Folder 2)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: N-Z, 1991 (Box 2127, Folder 3)
  - Individuals M-R (Box 2128)
  - Individuals S-Z (Box 2129)
  - Harriet Corinne Gould scrapbook (Box 2155.1)
  - Evelyn Elizabeth Hibbard scrapbooks (Box 2155.2)
- Class of 1942 Records, 1938-2002; 9.417 linear feet (20 containers)
  The Class of 1942 was the sixty-fourth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1942 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1942, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, letters, questionnaires, and other memorabilia.
  Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
  Researchers must sign an access form to use the microfilm for the Class of 1942's 15th [1957] reunion questionnaires.
  - Commencement, 1942 (Box 2130, Folder 1)
  - Commencement Music, 1942 (Box 2130, Folder 2)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1942 (Box 2130, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1942 (Box 2130, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1938-1939 (Box 2130, Folder 5)
  - Groups, 1938-1942 (Box 2130, Folder 6)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1942 (Box 2130, Folder 7)
  - Ivy Day-Photographs, 1942 (Box 2130, Folder 8)
  - Junior Prom, 1941 (Box 2130, Folder 9)
  - Junior Ushers, 1941 (Box 2130, Folder 10)
  - Class Letters, 1943-2002 (Box 2130, Folder 11)
  - Class Officers, 1938-1942 (Box 2130, Folder 12)
  - Reunions, 1947 (Box 2130, Folder 13)
  - Reunions, 1952 (Box 2130, Folder 14)
  - Reunions, 1957 (Box 2130, Folder 15)
  - 15th reunion questionnaires [microfilm], 1957 (Box 2130, Folder microfilm)
    General
  - Reunions, 1962 (Box 2130, Folder 16)
  - Reunions, 1967 (Box 2130, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 1972 (Box 2130, Folder 18)
  - Reunions, 1977-1982 (Box 2130, Folder 19)
  - Reunions, 1980 (Box 2130, Folder 20)
  - Reunions, 1987 (Box 2130, Folder 21)
  - Reunions, 1992 (Box 2130, Folder 22)
  - Reunions, 1997 (Box 2130, Folder 23)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1940 (Box 2131, Folder 1)
  - Sophomore Push Committee, 1940 (Box 2131, Folder 2)
  - Reunion Questionnaire, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 1)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: A-D, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 2)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: E-H, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 3)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: I-L, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 4)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: M-P, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 5)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Q-T, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 6)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: U-Z, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 7)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 8)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 9)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 10)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 11)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 12)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 13)
  - Reunion Questionnaire: Anonymous, 1992 (Box 2132, Folder 14)
  - Harriet Bixler, Class of 1942, photograph album, 1938-1942; 2018-A-0023; Naughton, Harriet (Bix) Bixler, Class of 1942; Katherine S. Naughton; .5 linear feet (1 legal clamshell box) (Box 1)
    Photograph album containing photographs and other school and personal memorabilia of Harriet Bixler, Class of 1942
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Donated by Katherine S. Naughton
    photograph albums; Katherine S. Naughton
  - Reunion questionnaire, 1992 (Box 2132.1)
  - Clare Beirne (Box 2132.2)
  - Caroline Chandler class notes (Box 2133)
  - Caroline Chandler class notes (Box 2134)
  - Caroline Chandler class notes (Box 2135)
  - Caroline Chandler class notes (Box 2136)
  - Caroline Chandler class notes (Box 2136.1)
  - Barbara Ramseyer class notes and reminiscence (Box 2137)
  - Ellen Saville (Box 2137.1)
  - Reunion letters, 1977-1992 (Box 2138)
  - Betty-Ann Davis memorabilia book (Box 2138.1)
  - Sociology survey, 1989 (Box 1238.2)
  - Reunions materials, 1972-1992 (Box 2130.2)
  - Reunion materials, 1992-1993 (Box 2130.3)
  - Reunion, 1997-2018 (Box 2130.4)
  - Con-Reunions, 1967 (Box 2130.1)
- Class of 1943 Records, 1939-2003; 8 boxes (6.5 linear feet)
  The Class of 1943 was the sixty-fifth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1943 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1943, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, and other memorabilia.
  - Alumnae Fund Agent Letters, 1953-1990 (Box 2139, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 2)
  - Commencement-Last Chapel, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Photographs, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Speaker, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 5)
  - Class Dinner, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 6)
  - Float Night, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 7)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1939-1940 (Box 2139, Folder 8)
  - General, 1940 (Box 2139, Folder 9)
  - Groups, 1939-1943; 1964-1965; 1984; 1991; undated (Box 2139, Folder 10)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 11)
  - Ivy Day-Photographs, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 12)
  - Junior Prom, 1942 (Box 2139, Folder 13)
  - Junior Ushers, 1942 (Box 2139, Folder 14)
  - Class Letters, 1948-2003 (Box 2139, Folder 15)
  - Mascot, 1953 (Box 2139, Folder 16)
  - Class Officers, 1967-1993 (Box 2139, Folder 17)
  - Class Officers-Photographs, 1940 (Box 2139, Folder 18)
  - Rally Day, 1943 (Box 2139, Folder 19)
  - Reunions, 1948 (Box 2139, Folder 20)
  - Reunions, 1953-1958 (Box 2139, Folder 21)
  - Reunions, 1963 (Box 2139, Folder 22)
  - Reunions, 1968 (Box 2139, Folder 23)
  - Reunions, 1973 (Box 2139, Folder 24)
  - Reunions, 1978 (Box 2139, Folder 25)
  - Reunions, 1983 (Box 2139, Folder 26)
  - Reunions, 1988 (Box 2139, Folder 27)
  - Reunions-Photographs, 1988 (Box 2139, Folder 28)
  - Reunions, 1993 (Box 2139.1, Folder 1)
  - Reunions, 1998 (Box 2139.1, Folder 2)
  - Reunions, 2003 (Box 2139.1, Folder 3)
  - Reunions-Accounts of 60th Reunion, 2003 (Box 2139.1, Folder 4)
  - Rules and Regulations, 1942-1943 (Box 2139.1, Folder 5)
  - Class Secretary (See OV) (Box 2139.1, Folder 6)
  - Songs, 1943 (Box 2139.1, Folder 7)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1941 (Box 2139.1, Folder 8)
  - Sophomore Push Committee, 1941 (Box 2139.1, Folder 9)
  - War Service, 1943-1945 (Box 2139.1, Folder 10)
  - Class Secretary's Scrapbook, 1943-1946; 1962-1968 (Box OV)
  - Class Secretary's Scrapbook-Reunion Pictures, 1958-1988 (Box OV)
  - Reunion Scrapbooks, 1948 (Box OV)
  - Reunion Scrapbooks, 1963 (Box OV)
  - Individuals A-L (Box 2140)
    Includes Nancy Davis (Reagen)
  - Individuals M-Z (Box 2141)
  - Class Secretary's scrapbooks, 1943-1946; 1963-1968 (Box 2141.1)
  - Class secretary's scrapbooks, reunion photos, 1958-1988 (Box 2155.4)
  - 5th class reunion scrapbook, 1948 (Box 2155.5)
  - 20th class reunion scrapboon, 1963 (Box 2155.6)
- Class of 1944 Records, 1940-2004; 12 boxes (5.8 linear feet)
  The Class of 1944 was the sixty-sixth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1944 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1944, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, and other memorabilia.
  - Baccalaureate Sunday, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 2)
  - Commencement-Photographs, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 3)
  - Commencement-Speaker, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1940-1941 (Box 2142, Folder 5)
  - Groups, 1940-1944 (Box 2142, Folder 6)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 7)
  - Ivy Day, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 8)
  - Class Letters, 1966-1975; 2004 (Box 2142, Folder 9)
  - Officers, 1943 (Box 2142, Folder 10)
  - Reunions, 1949 (Box 2142, Folder 11)
  - Reunions, 1954 (Box 2142, Folder 12)
  - Reunions, 1959 (Box 2142, Folder 13)
  - Reunions, 1964 (Box 2142, Folder 14)
  - Reunions, 1969 (Box 2142, Folder 15)
  - Reunions, 1974 (Box 2142, Folder 16)
  - Reunions, 1979 (Box 2142, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 1981 (Box 2142, Folder 18)
  - Reunions, 1984 (Box 2142, Folder 19)
  - Reunions, 1989 (Box 2142, Folder 20)
  - Reunions, 1994 (Box 2142, Folder 21)
  - Reunions, undated (Box 2142, Folder 22)
  - Reunion Newsletter, 1994-2002 (Box 2142, Folder 23)
  - Senior Day, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 24)
  - Songs, 1940-1944 (Box 2142, Folder 25)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1942 (Box 2142, Folder 26)
  - Sophomore Push, 1942 (Box 2142, Folder 27)
  - Class Supper, 1944 (Box 2142, Folder 28)
  - Individuals A-Rau (Box 2143)
  - Individuals Rid-Z (Box 2144)
  - Elizabeth Haynes (Box 2144.1)
  - Euphemia K. (Steffey)Hare (Box 2145)
  - Ruth Dorothy Honaman correspondence (Box 2146)
  - Janet Kedney correspondence and other materials (Box 2147)
  - Marilyn Lahmer class notes and memorabilia (Box 2148, Box 2149)
  - Margaret McClumpha correspondence (Box 2150)
  - Alice E. Ridenour memorabilia books (Box 2150.1)
  - Class scrapbooks, 1944-1983 (Box 2150.2)
- Class of 1945 Records, 1941-2005; 6 boxes (2.9 linear feet); 3.125 linear feet (5 containers)
  The Class of 1945 was the sixty-seventh graduating class of Smith College. As part of an accelerated war-time program, 100 students of the Class of 1945 graduated in August, 1944.
  The Class of 1945 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1945, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, memory books, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 1)
  - Commencement-August, 1944 (Box 2151, Folder 2)
  - Commencement-Photographs, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 3)
  - Commencement-Speaker, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Dance, 1941 (Box 2151, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1941-1942 (Box 2151, Folder 6)
  - General, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 7)
  - Groups, 1941-1945 (Box 2151, Folder 8)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 9)
  - Ivy Day, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 10)
  - Ivy Day-Photographs, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 11)
  - Class Letters, 1967-2003 (Box 2151, Folder 12)
  - Mountain Day, 1942 (Box 2151, Folder 13)
  - Officers, 1941 (Box 2151, Folder 14)
  - Reunions, 1946 (Box 2151, Folder 15)
  - Reunions, 1954 (Box 2151, Folder 16)
  - Reunions, 1965 (Box 2151, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 1970 (Box 2151, Folder 18)
  - Reunions-Photographs, 1970 (Box 2151, Folder 19)
  - Reunions, 1975-1980 (Box 2151, Folder 20)
  - Reunions, 1995 (Box 2151, Folder 21)
  - Reunions, 2000 (Box 2151, Folder 22)
  - Reunions-Wartime Questionnaire, 2000 (Box 2151, Folder 23)
  - Songs, 1945; undated (Box 2151, Folder 24)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1943 (Box 2151, Folder 25)
  - Class Supper, 1945 (Box 2151, Folder 26)
  - Reunion Book, 1995 (Box 2152, Folder 1)
  - 55th Reunion Newsletters, 1995-2002 (Box 2152, Folder 2)
  - Reunion Memories Book, 1995 (Box 2152, Folder 3)
  - Reunion Photographs, 1995 (Box 2152, Folder 4)
  - Reunions, 2005 (Box 2152, Folder 5)
  - Individuals A-G (Box 2153)
  - Individuals H-Z (Box 2154)
  - Shirley Traver scrapbook, 1941-1945 (Box 2153.1)
  - Myers, Mary Gertrude: Letters home, Photo at Emerson House (Box 2154.1)
- Class of 1946 Records, 1942-2002; 2.667 linear feet (6 containers)
  The Class of 1946 was the sixty-eighth graduating class of Smith College. As part of a war-time acceleration program, some members of the Class of 1946 graduated in August, 1945.
  The Class of 1946 records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1946, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 1)
  - Commencement-August, 1945 (Box 2155, Folder 2)
  - Commencement-Music, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 3)
  - Commencement-Photographs, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 4)
  - Ivy Day, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 5)
  - Ivy Day, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1942-1943 (Box 2155, Folder 7)
  - General, 1943 (Box 2155, Folder 8)
  - Groups, 1942-1946 (Box 2155, Folder 9)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 10)
  - Class Letters, 1967-2002 (Box 2155, Folder 11)
  - Mountain Day, 1942 (Box 2155, Folder 12)
  - News Clippings, undated (Box 2155, Folder 13)
  - Officers, 1942-1946 (Box 2155, Folder 14)
  - Reunions, 1951-1966 (Box 2155, Folder 15)
  - Reunions, 1971 (Box 2155, Folder 16)
  - Reunions, 1976-1981 (Box 2155, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 1991 (Box 2155, Folder 18)
  - Reunions, 1996 (Box 2155, Folder 19)
  - Reunions-Newsletters, 1996-2001 (Box 2155, Folder 20)
  - Songs, undated (Box 2155, Folder 21)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1944 (Box 2155, Folder 22)
  - Sophomore Push, 1944 (Box 2155, Folder 23)
  - Class Supper, 1946 (Box 2155, Folder 24)
  - Year Book, undated (Box 2155, Folder 25)
  - Reunion Book, 1996 (Box 2155, Folder 26)
  - Letters, photographs, and reunion memorabilia, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Joan Lundberg scrapbook, and Junior Year Abroad in Mexico materials (Box 2156)
  - Individuals A-Z (Box 2157)
  - Araxi Allalemdjian class notes, papers, photographs (Box 2158)
  - 50th reunion photo album (Box 2158.1)
- Class of 1947 Records, 1943-2002; 13.937 linear feet (12 containers)
  The Class of 1947 was the sixty-ninth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1947 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1947, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, treasury information, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 1)
  - Commencement-Music, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 2)
  - Commencement-Photographs, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 3)
  - Commencement-Speaker, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 4)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1943-1944 (Box 2159, Folder 5)
  - General, 1943-1944 (Box 2159, Folder 6)
  - Groups, 1943-1947; 1981 (Box 2159, Folder 7)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 8)
  - Ivy Day, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 9)
  - Ivy Day-Photographs, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 10)
  - Junior Prom, 1946 (Box 2159, Folder 11)
  - Junior Ushers, 1946 (Box 2159, Folder 12)
  - Class Letters, 1957-1994 (Box 2159, Folder 13)
  - Officers, 1943-1947 (Box 2159, Folder 14)
  - Questionnaire, 1967 (Box 2159, Folder 15)
  - Reunions, 1948 (Box 2159, Folder 16)
  - Reunions, 1952 (Box 2159, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 1957 (Box 2159, Folder 18)
  - Reunions, 1962 (Box 2159, Folder 19)
  - Reunions, 1967 (Box 2159, Folder 20)
  - Reunions, 1972 (Box 2159, Folder 21)
  - Reunions, 1977-1982 (Box 2159, Folder 22)
  - Reunions, 1987 (Box 2159, Folder 23)
  - Reunions, 1992 (Box 2159, Folder 24)
  - Reunions, 1997-2002 (Box 2159, Folder 25)
  - Reunion Songs, 1952 (Box 2159, Folder 26)
  - Songs, undated (Box 2159, Folder 27)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1945 (Box 2159, Folder 28)
  - Step Sings, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 29)
  - Class Supper, 1947 (Box 2159, Folder 30)
  - Treasurer, 1962-1998 (Box 2159, Folder 31)
  - Reunions (Box 2160)
  - Pauline Perry scrapbook (Box 2155.3)
  - Frances Starks Heyburn and Joan Leiman scrapbooks (Box 2160.1)
  - Alice Parker music scores (Box 2160.2)
  - Mary Batchelder scrapbook (Box 2160.3)
  - Joan Leiman scrapbook (Box 2160.4)
  - Joan Leiman scrapbook (Box 2160.5)
  - Joan Sanderson memorabilia books, 1946-1947 (Box 2160.6)
  - Joan Sanderson memorabilia book, 1945-1946 (Box 2160.7)
  - Joan Sanderson memorabilia book, 1944-1945 (Box 2160.8)
  - Edith Scott scrapbook (Box 2160.10)
- Class of 1948 Records, 1944-2003; 3.542 linear feet (7 containers)
  The Class of 1948 was the seventieth graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1948 Records, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1948, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, financial information, class surveys, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 1)
  - Commencement-Photographs, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 2)
  - Commencement-Speaker, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1983 (Box 2161, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Alumnae House, 1981-1987 (Box 2161, Folder 5)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1944-1945 (Box 2161, Folder 6)
  - Fundraising Appeal, undated (Box 2161, Folder 7)
  - General, 1944-1945 (Box 2161, Folder 8)
  - Groups, 1944-1948 (Box 2161, Folder 9)
  - Hoop Rolling, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 10)
  - Ivy Day, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 11)
  - Ivy Day-Photographs, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 12)
  - Junior Prom, 1947 (Box 2161, Folder 13)
  - Last Sing, 1948 (Box 2161, Folder 14)
  - Class Letters, 1958-2003 (Box 2161, Folder 15)
  - List of Deceased Alumnae, 1987 (Box 2161, Folder 16)
  - Officers, 1944-1948 (Box 2161, Folder 17)
  - Reunions, 1949-1968 (Box 2161, Folder 18)
  - Reunions, 1973-1978 (Box 2161, Folder 19)
  - Reunions, 1973-1978 (Box 2161, Folder 20)
  - Reunions, 1983 (Box 2161, Folder 21)
  - Reunions, 1988 (Box 2161, Folder 22)
  - Reunions, 1993 (Box 2162, Folder 1)
  - Reunions, 1998-2002 (Box 2162, Folder 2)
  - Reunion Photographs, undated (Box 2162, Folder 3)
  - Senior Prom, 1948 (Box 2162, Folder 4)
  - Songs, undated (Box 2162, Folder 5)
  - Sophomore Carnival, 1946 (Box 2162, Folder 6)
  - Class Supper, 1948 (Box 2162, Folder 7)
  - Class Surveys A-J, 1981-1983 (Box 2162, Folder 8)
  - Class Surveys K-R, 1981-1983 (Box 2162, Folder 9)
  - Class Surveys S-Z, 1981-1983 (Box 2162, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer, 1952; 1983-1993 (Box 2162, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer-Attempt to get tax exempt status, 1993-1995 (Box 2162, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer-Class Dues, 1951-1973 (Box 2162, Folder 13)
  - Individuals A-Tu (Box 2163)
  - Individuals Ty-Z (Box 2164)
  - Miscellaneous individuals (Box 2164.1)
  - Marilyn Heyman memorabilia book (Box 2165)
  - Jean Winans Coe scrapbook and photo album, 1946-1947 (Box 2165.1)
- Class of 1949 Records, 1945-2004; 7 boxes (2.9 linear feet); 3.708 linear feet (9 containers)
  The Class of 1949 was the seventy-first graduating class of Smith College.
  The Class of 1949 Records contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1949, including materials from commencement, reunions, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and other memorabilia.
  - Commencement, 1949 (Box 2166, Folder 1)